阿甘！
Gump!
你到部队来干什么？
What's your sole purpose in this army?
干你叫我干的事 教官！
To do whatever you tell me, Drill Sergeant!
他妈的 阿甘 你他妈的真是个天才
God damn it, Gump, you're a goddamn genius.
这是我听过的最了不起的回答
That's the most outstanding answer I've ever heard .
你他妈的智商一定有一百六
You must have a goddamn I.Q Of 160.
你他妈的真有天赋 列兵阿甘
You are goddamn gifted, Private Gump.
大家都听着！
Listen up, people!
不知什么原因 我很适合当兵
Now for some reason, I fit in the army
就像一对插销那么适合
Like one of them round pegs.
真实一点都不苦
It's not really hard.
你只需把你的床铺好
You just make your bed neat,
记着要站得笔直
remember to stand up straight,
不管回答什么问题
and always answer every question
都说“是 教官”
with "Yes, Drill Sergeant. "
听清楚没有？
Is that clear?
是 教官！
Yes, Drill Sergeant!
你只需要沿着海底拖你的网
What you do is drag your nets along the bottom.
在一个好天气
On a good day,
你一次就能捕到上百磅的虾
you can catch over a hundred pounds of shrimp.
如果一切顺利
Everything goes all right,
两个人捕10个小时的虾
2 men shrimping 10 hours ,
减去你用掉的油费
Less what you spends on gas...
完成了 教官！
Done, Drill Sergeant!
阿甘！
Gump!
为什么你这么快就把枪装好了？
Why did you put that weapon together so quickly?
你叫我这么做的 教官
You told me to, Drill Sergeant.
耶稣基督啊
Jesus H. Christ.
这是新的连队纪录
This is a new company record .
如果不是因为
If it wasn't a waste
我们这儿兵源不足
of a fine enlisted man,
我会推荐你上军官预备学校 列兵阿甘
I'd recommend you for O.C.S., Private Gump.
有朝一日你会当上将军！
You're going to be a general someday!
现在把你的枪拆开重装一遍！
Now disassemble your weapon and continue!
总之 就像我说过的
Anyway, like I was saying,
虾是海里最好的东西
shrimp is the fruit of the sea.
你可以烧它、煮它、烤它
You can barbecue it, boil it, broil it,
烘它、炒它
bake it, saute it.
把它做成串烧虾、克洛虾
They's, uh, shrimp kabobs, shrimp creole,
鲜虾羹、铁板虾、油炸虾
shrimp gumbo, pan fried, deep fried,
脆皮虾
stir fried.
还有菠萝虾
There's pineapple shrimp
柠檬虾、椰子虾
and lemon shrimp, coconut shrimp,
胡椒虾
pepper shrimp,
鲜虾汤、油焖虾
shrimp soup, shrimp stew ,
虾肉色拉
shrimp salad,
土豆虾
shrimp in potatoes,
虾肉汉堡包
shrimp burger,
虾肉三明治
shrimp sandwich.
还有…差不多就这些了
That...That's about it.